<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Daily WordReference</title>
    <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/"/>
    <updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>WordReference</name>
    </author>
    <id>id</id>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: nag</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/10/intermediate-word-of-the-day-nag/"/>
        <id>post-15578</id>
        <updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>nag (verb, noun) /næg/ LISTEN Teenagers often think their parents are nagging them. Nag is a word used informally among native speakers. It means ‘to annoy by constant demands or criticism,’ or ‘to be the cause of pain, irritation, or unease.’ Even more informally, a nag is a person who nags and irritates other people all the time. Example sentences Every summer my husband nags me about putting on sunblock; he&#039;s right of course, because I burn easily and I always forget! Henry went to see the doctor about a pain that had been nagging him for some time. The painter was always nagged by doubts about how good her work was. My boss is such a nag and never just leaves us alone to get on with the job. Words often used with nag You can also use nag without a direct object, in which case it takes the preposition “at.” Example: “The idea that she had left the oven on kept nagging at Frances.” Nag is also used without an object and with the adverb “on” to mean that someone keeps nagging. Example: “Teenagers often complain that their parents are always nagging on about how much TV they watch.” In pop culture Listen to Joan Jett and the Blackhearts singing “Nag” here: Additional information A nag is also a horse, usually an old horse that someone considers worthless. Did you know? When talking about a person nagging or being a nag, the word used to mainly be associated with women. However, in these less sexist times, most people recognize that both men and women can nag a lot! Other forms nagger (noun) Origin Nag, meaning ‘to annoy by scolding,’ is a relatively new term, and dates back to the early 19th century. Its origin is uncertain, but it is thought to have evolved from a dialectal term, nag, that meant ‘to gnaw,’ and probably came from a Scandinavian source. As such, it can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic gnagan (to gnaw). Nag is related to the Old Norse gnaga (‘to complain,’ but literally ‘to bite or gnaw’) and the dialectal Swedish and Norwegian nagga (to gnaw), as well as the Old Saxon gnagan, the Old Norse and Swedish gnaga, the Middle Dutch and Dutch knagen, the Old High German gnagan and the German nagen (all meaning ‘to gnaw’), and of course the English word gnaw. The noun meaning ‘a person who nags’ dates back to the mid-19th century, and comes from the verb. Nag, meaning ‘a riding pony’ and ‘an old horse,’ dates back to around the year 1400, in the form of the Middle English noun nagge. Its origin is uncertain, but it is thought to be related to the word neigh, of imitative origin. See full definition Learn more about nag in our forums Nag in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: ring</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/10/basic-word-of-the-day-ring/"/>
        <id>post-15548</id>
        <updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>ring (noun, verb) past tense: rang LISTEN A ring is a circular band, usually of gold or another metal, worn on the finger. Marie&#039;s engagement ring had an emerald and two small diamonds. George wore the class ring that he got when he graduated from the university. A ring can be something shaped like a ring. The children held hands and danced in a ring. The cigar smoker blew smoke rings. Ring also means ‘to make a loud echoing sound as that of a bell.’ Someone is ringing the doorbell. Would you please answer it? The church bells ring before Sunday mass. Common uses give someone a ring: to call someone on the telephone. Example: “I don’t know if we can come to your party, but I’ll give you a ring as soon as I know.” Did you know? A boxing ring is the space where a boxing (fighting with padded gloves) match takes place. Modern boxing rings are square, but we still call them rings because in the past, people fought inside a circle drawn on the ground. In pop culture Listen to Johnny Cash sing “Ring of Fire.” This song compares love to a ring of fire. Do you think that is a good comparison? There are other meanings of ring. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: blend</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/09/intermediate-word-of-the-day-blend/"/>
        <id>post-15583</id>
        <updated>2022-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>blend (verb, noun) /blɛnd/ LISTEN A woman using a blender To blend means ‘to mix two or more things smoothly‘ or ‘to combine in a really nice way.’ It also means ‘to have no separation that can be easily seen.’ As a noun, you might have heard the word blend in wines or teas; this is because blend means ‘a mixture produced by blending.’ Example sentences Leave the soup to simmer for fifteen minutes and then blend it until smooth. The artist blended the colors skillfully. The choir&#039;s voices blended perfectly. Some animals have coloring that allows them to blend into the background. Saint-Émilion is a wine made from a blend of grape varieties. In pop culture A blended family is one where the parents have children from previous relationships. The movie Blended is about the beginnings of such a family, and you can watch the trailer for it here: Additional information In linguistics, a blend is a word made up of a combination of two words, like brunch, which is made up of breakfast and lunch. Words like this are also called portmanteau words. Did you know? A blender is a common kitchen appliance. It is the tall, motorized machine that you can use to make juice, smoothies, milkshakes, etc. There is also a similar appliance called a stick blender, or immersion blender, which has a similar effect but is much smaller and can be held in the hand and immersed, or put, into the thing you are blending. Other forms blender (noun) Origin Blend, meaning ‘to mix something until the parts become indistinguishable’ or ‘to stir a liquid,’ dates back to around the year 1300, in the form of the Middle English verb blenden. Its origin is uncertain. Some linguists think that it evolved from the Old English blendan or blondan (to mix), while others think it came into English from the (related) Old Norse blanda (to mix). It’s possible that it evolved as a combination of both. Either way, blend can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic blandan (‘to mix,’ literally ‘to make cloudy’) and the Proto-Indo-European root bhel– (to shine, flash or burn), and is related to the Old Saxon and Old High German blantan (to mix), the Middle Dutch blanden (to mix), the Gothic blandan (to mix), the Old Church Slavonic blesti (to go astray), the German Blendling (bastard or mongrel) and the Danish blande (to mix), as well as the Sanskrit bhrajate (shines), the Greek phlegein (to burn), the Latin flamma (flame), fulmen (lightning) and fulgere (to shine or flash), the Lithuanian balnas (pale) and blandus (troubled, stupid or thick), and English words such as black, blanch, blanket, blaze, bleach, bleak, blind, blond, blue, blushflagrant, flame and flamingo. The figurative sense, ‘to mingle closely,’ first appeared in the early 14th century. The noun, meaning ‘a mixture formed by blending,’ comes from the verb, and dates back to the mid-19th century. See full definition Learn more about blend in our forums Blend in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: fate</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/09/basic-word-of-the-day-fate/"/>
        <id>post-15547</id>
        <updated>2022-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>fate (noun) LISTEN I see your fate in the crystal ball. Someone’s fate is something that unavoidably happens to that person. Trevor&#039;s fate was determined by the choices he made as a teenager. Fate also means ‘destiny.’ Sally knew that it was her fate to become president of the country. It was Leslie&#039;s fate to marry Mike. Fate can also mean ‘death’ or ‘destruction.’ Many soldiers met their fate at the Battle of Gettysburg. Don&#039;t confuse it with faith: belief in the teachings of a religion. Example: “The Jedi had faith in the Force.” Common uses fate worse than death: a tragedy that would make life not worth living. Example: “When the soldiers arrived, the villagers suffered a fate worse than death.” In pop culture A twist of fate is an everyday event that happens by chance and is strange or has major importance. A Simple Twist of Fate is also a movie about a small child who wanders into a man’s home and it changes his life. Watch the trailer for this movie. There are other meanings of fate. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: rocket</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/06/intermediate-word-of-the-day-rocket/"/>
        <id>post-15570</id>
        <updated>2022-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>rocket (noun, verb) /ˈrɑkɪt/ LISTEN A rocket is any tube-like device that contains fuel, which burns and makes it fly through the air; it can be used for fireworks, signaling, etc. A rocket is also a space capsule put into orbit. As a verb, it means ‘to transport with a rocket,’ ‘to move very rapidly,’ and, informally, ‘to increase suddenly.’ Rocket has another completely different meaning; as a noun, it is a Mediterranean plant used in green leaf salads, although it is more commonly known as arugula in US English. Example sentences The fireworks display organizers saved a big rocket for the finale. The policeman sent up a rocket as a warning. Crowds of people gathered to see the rocket launch into space. The spaceship was rocketed into orbit. The car rocketed along the highway. Prices have rocketed since last year. Harry added some rocket leaves to his sandwich. Words often used with rocket it’s not rocket science: an expression meaning that something is not really very complicated. Example: “Haven’t you finished doing your homework yet? Come on; it’s not rocket science!” A similar expression with the same meaning is “It’s not brain surgery.” give someone a rocket (UK): reprimand someone severely, get very mad at someone. Example: “The boss gave Joe a rocket when he arrived 30 minutes late for an important meeting.” In pop culture Someone who works on rockets, like a scientist or engineer, is called a rocketeer. The Rocketeer is the title of a 1991 movie and you can see the trailer for it here: Did you know? In English we also have the related word skyrocket. This word can refer to a kind of rocket, but (perhaps more commonly) it is an informal verb meaning ‘to increase a lot’ or ‘to increase astronomically.’ Example: “The cost of US colleges has skyrocketed since my parents were kids.” Skyrocket is the opposite of plummet, one of our first Words of the Day. Other forms rocketlike (adjective) Origin Rocket, meaning ‘a self-propelling device,’ dates back to the early 17th century. It came into English from the Italian rochetto (a bobbin), the diminutive of rocca (a distaff, which is a device used for spinning thread). It is thought to have come into Italian from a Germanic source, and can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic rukkon– and the Proto-Indo-European root rug– (fabric or spun yarn). Rocket is, therefore, related to the Old High German rocko, the Old Norse rokkr, the German Rocken, the Swedish rock and the Icelandic rokkur (all meaning ‘a distaff’). The sense ‘a fuel-propelled device,’ first used for fireworks, dates back to the early 20th century. The verb, which originally meant ‘to attack with rockets,’ dates back to the late 18th century, and comes from the noun. The sense ‘to spring like a rocket’ was first used in the mid-19th century. Rocket, the noun meaning ‘a leafy green plant used in salads,’ is a bit older; it dates back to around the year 1500. It came into English from the Middle French noun roquette, which was in turn borrowed from the Italian rochetta, diminutive for ruca (a type of cabbage). It can be traced back to the Latin eruca (colewort), which is related to ericus (‘hedgehog’ or ‘beam with spikes’) and the Proto-Indo-European root ghers– (to bristle). Rocket, in this sense, is related to the Sanskrit harsate (bristles), the Avestan zarshayamna– (ruffling your feathers) and the Welsh garw (rough), as well as the English arugula and many other modern terms for the plant, and the English word horror. See full definition Learn more about rocket in our forums Rocket in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: former</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/06/basic-word-of-the-day-former/"/>
        <id>post-15539</id>
        <updated>2022-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>former (adjective, noun) LISTEN His former girlfriend moved out. Former means ‘having been in the past.’ Eric&#039;s former boss is now working for another company. Thomas&#039;s former school is hosting his class reunion. Former also means ‘being the first of two mentioned.’ (The second is the latter). The former choice was better than the latter. Common uses a shell of his/her former self: someone who has changed for the worse, usually because of a traumatic experience. Example: “After the war, Scarlett was a shell of her former self.” Did you know? Ex– is a more casual way to say former. For example: “Dan’s ex-wife is the mother of his oldest daughter.” And when referring to a former spouse or partner, someone may just say ex. For example: “Oh no! There’s my ex. We need to leave immediately.” In pop culture The five former presidents of the US spoke at a charity concert to help victims of Hurricane Harvey in Texas. You can hear Bill Clinton and Barack Obama speak in this video. There are other meanings of former. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: knack</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/05/intermediate-word-of-the-day-knack/"/>
        <id>post-15569</id>
        <updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>knack (noun) /næk/ LISTEN Sylvia has a knack for math. Knack is a word used informally to mean ‘a skill or ability’ and it can also mean ‘a clever way of doing something.’ Knack also means ‘a particular talent for doing something’ or ‘a tendency to do something.’ Example sentences Sylvia has a real knack with children; they adore her. The washing machine does work, but you have to press the button a certain way; there&#039;s a knack to it. Alicia has a knack for computer programming and works for a tech company in San Francisco. Melanie has a knack of picking the wrong boyfriends; they always end up breaking her heart. In pop culture Listen to the Knack’s “My Sharona” here: Don&#039;t confuse it with The term knackered sounds similar but means something completely different. It is very common in the UK, especially in informal conversation, and means ‘extremely tired.’ For example, “I was knackered last night and slept for 12 hours.” It is not very common in the US, where we would just say “really tired” or something similar. Did you know? Knack can be used with either “for” or “of” when talking about a talent or tendency. Some dictionaries say that “knack of” should be used with a behavior or tendency (ie, “a knack of picking the wrong boyfriends”) and “knack for” should be used for a skill (ie, “a knack for computer programming”), but many native speakers don’t know about this rule. Origin Knack, which originally meant ‘a deception, trick or device,’ dates back to the mid-14th century. Its origin is uncertain, but some linguists think it may have come from another, slightly older (early 14th century) Middle English word, knak or knakke, which meant ‘a sharp-sounding blow or sound,’ which probably came into English from a Germanic language, and was originally imitative. Knack is possibly related to the German knacken (to crack), and the English words knap (a sharp-sounding blow) and crack. The sense ‘a special ability for something’ was first used in the late 16th century, though some linguists actually think knack in this sense could have been a separate word, also of unknown origin. See full definition Learn more about knack in our forums Knack in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: jar</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/05/basic-word-of-the-day-jar/"/>
        <id>post-15538</id>
        <updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>jar (noun, verb) past tense: jarred LISTEN A jar of pickles A jar is a glass container that you put things in. Martin opened the jar of strawberry jam. Emma took a chocolate chip cookie from the cookie jar. Jar also means ‘to suddenly vibrate or shake.’ The earthquake jarred the house. The fire alarm jarred me from my sleep. Did you know? Some homes have a swear jar to discourage family members or roommates from using vulgar language. Every time someone swears (says a bad word), they have to put money in the jar. Related words ajar: slightly opened, when referring to a door. Example: “The door was ajar, so she heard their conversation.” In pop culture Watch this clip from the TV show Glee, which takes place at a high school prom (dance). The song is “Jar of Hearts.” You can sing along with the chorus: “Who do you think you are?/Running around leaving scars/Collecting your jar of hearts/Tearing love apart/ You’re going to catch a cold/From the ice inside your soul/Don’t come back for me.” There are other meanings of jar. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: nail</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/04/intermediate-word-of-the-day-nail/"/>
        <id>post-15568</id>
        <updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>nail (noun, verb) /neɪl/ LISTEN As a noun, a nail is the hard cover on the tip of each of our fingers and toes, as well as a thin piece of metal with a pointed end used to connect things to a wall or to each other. As a verb, nail means not only ‘to fasten or connect something with a nail,’ but also, as slang, ‘to arrest or catch a criminal’ or ‘to achieve something with great success.’ Example sentences I need to cut my nails; they&#039;re getting too long! Helen hammered a nail into the wall so she could hang the picture. Eugene nailed two pieces of wood together. After a car chase, the police finally nailed the bank robbers. I&#039;m sure Patricia will have nailed the exam; she&#039;s worked so hard. Words often used with nail nailed it!: an interjection used to say you have successfully achieved something. Example: “How did your job interview go?” “Nailed it! I start on Monday.” fight tooth and nail: an expression used figuratively to mean you will do everything in your power to achieve or combat something: Example: “The MP fought tooth and nail to get the new law accepted.” “The residents fought tooth and nail against the plans for the new road.” on the nail: immediately. Example: “The seller wanted to be paid cash on the nail.” hit the nail on the head: get something exactly right or understand something correctly. Example: “When you said my problem might be an allergy, you hit the nail on the head; that’s exactly what it turned out to be.” the final nail (in the coffin): the last in a series of misfortunes leading to someone or something’s downfall. Example: “When his van broke down, that was the final nail in the coffin for Alan’s delivery business.” fingernail: a nail on your finger toenail: a nail on your toe In pop culture Watch the trailer for Netflix’s cooking show Nailed It! here: Did you know? As a slang term, nail someone can mean ‘to have sexual intercourse with that person.’ It is normally said of a man having sexual intercourse with a woman. You may hear this a lot in movies and on TV, but it is generally considered demeaning and offensive to talk about someone like this. Other forms nailless (adjective) Origin Nail dates back to before the year 900, in the form of what some linguists believe were two separate Old English nouns: nægl (finger or toenail) and negel (sharp metal pin), which had merged by Middle English, and perhaps even sooner, to nail(i) or nayl(l), which took on both meanings. Other linguists think that they are simply alternate spellings of the same noun, and the original meaning was ‘finger or toenail,’ as well as ‘claw,’ with ‘metal pin’ appearing soon after, a figurative take on claw. Either way, nail can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic naglaz and the Proto-Indo-European root (o)nog(h)– (nail), and is related to the Old Saxon and Old High German nagel, the Old Frisian neil, the Middle Dutch naghel, the Dutch nagel, the German Nagel, the Danish negl and the Swedish nagel (all of which have both meanings of nail), as well as the Greek onyx (claw or fingernail), the Latin unguis (nail or claw), the Spanish uña, Portuguese unha and French ongle (together with other Romance language words for nail or claw), the Old Church Slavonic noga (foot) and noguti (nail or claw), the Lithuanian naga (hoof) and nagutis (fingernail), the Old Irish ingen (nail or claw) and the Old Welsh eguin (nail or claw). The expression ‘to hit the nail on the head’ first appeared in the early 16th century. The verb also dates back to before the year 900, as the Old English næglian, meaning ‘to fasten with nails’ (Middle English naylen or nailen), which can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic ganaglijan, from the same PIE root as the noun. Nail is related to the Old Saxon neglian, the Old Norse negla, the Old High German negilen, the German nageln and the Gothic ganagljan, all meaning ‘to nail.’ The sense ‘to catch’ was first recorded in the mid-18th century, while ‘to succeed’ is from the late 19th century. See full definition Learn more about nail in our forums Nail in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: loose</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/04/basic-word-of-the-day-loose/"/>
        <id>post-15537</id>
        <updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>loose (adjective) LISTEN These jeans are too loose. Loose means ‘not fitting closely or tightly.’ A loose sweater looks good with tight jeans. After she lost weight, Pam&#039;s clothes were loose. Loose also means ‘free or released from being attached.’ Lila had a loose tooth. Don&#039;t confuse it with lose: a verb that means ‘to fail to keep.’ Example: “If you lose your keys you won’t get into the house.” Common uses hang loose: to stay calm (informal). Example: “Hang loose, man. Everything will be okay.” In pop culture Have you seen the movie “Footloose” starring Kevin Bacon? The word ‘footloose’ is an adjective that means “free, carefree,’ and the movie title is a wordplay because the main character is a dancer. There are other meanings of loose. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
    </feed>
