<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Daily WordReference</title>
    <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/"/>
    <updated>2022-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>WordReference</name>
    </author>
    <id>id</id>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: swipe</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/18/intermediate-word-of-the-day-swipe/"/>
        <id>post-15641</id>
        <updated>2022-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>swipe (noun, verb) /swaɪp/ LISTEN A swipe is a strong sweeping hit or blow—for example, with a golf club or cricket bat. Informally, a swipe is harsh criticism or a cutting remark. As a verb, to swipe means ‘to hit with a sweeping blow’ or, in US slang, ‘to steal.’ Swipe also means ‘to slide a magnetic card through a card reader’ or ‘to move your fingers across a touch screen.’ Example sentences With a swipe of her club, the golfer sent the ball flying toward the green. Don&#039;t take any notice of Paul; he&#039;s in a bad mood today and he&#039;s taking a swipe at everybody. The cricketer swiped at the ball. Nancy swiped $20 from her dad&#039;s wallet when he wasn&#039;t looking. Richard swiped his card to access the secure room. Swipe the screen to unlock the phone. Words often used with swipe swipe in/swipe out: to use a card or other magnetic device to get in or out of a door. Example: “The security at my office is quite high; all the employees have to swipe in and out.” In pop culture Love at First Swipe is a web series from Malaysia about finding love via a dating app. You can watch the trailer with English subtitles here: Did you know? The expressions swipe right and swipe left are used in the Tinder dating app, as literal instructions of what to do on your touch screen to show interest or disinterest in someone. Now people use these expressions colloquially to mean that they find someone attractive (swipe right) or unattractive (swipe left). Origin Swipe, meaning ‘a driving stroke with your arms in full swing,’ dates back to the early 19th century. Its origin is uncertain. Some linguists think it came from a dialectal variant of sweep, while others believe it evolved from a now obsolete noun, swip (a strike or blow). Some also point to different possible origins: the Middle English verb swope (to sweep with broad movements), or the obsolete nouns swaip (stroke or blow) or swape (oar or pole). Whichever of these is the true origin, they can all be traced back to the Proto-Germanic root swip-, and is related to the words sweep and swoop. The verb, originally meaning ‘to strike with a sweeping motion,’ also dates back to the early 19th century, and comes from the noun. The US slang sense, ‘to steal,’ dates back to the late 19th century, and is thought to have first appeared as prison slang. The credit card sense dates back to he 1990s, and the screen sense is from the early 21st century. See full definition Learn more about swipe in our forums Swipe in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: step</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/18/basic-word-of-the-day-step/"/>
        <id>post-15663</id>
        <updated>2022-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>step (noun, verb) past tense: stepped LISTEN A step is a movement made by lifting the foot and setting down, as in walking. Joan walks at least 10,000 steps every day. The dancers took two steps forward and three steps to the right. A step is also a stage in a procedure or process. The first step in the program is to admit you have a problem. When preparing food, the first step is to wash your hands. A step is a place for the foot when going up or down. There were eight steps on the ladder. The steps on the staircase were steep and narrow. Step means ‘to move in steps.’ &quot;If you step over to my desk, I&#039;ll show you how to load the software.&quot; &quot;Watch where you step. People ride horses on this path.&quot; Common uses step down: to resign. Example: “The mayor stepped down, because of the scandal.” step in: to intervene. Example: “The manager stepped in when her assistant could not help their client.” step out: to leave for a short time. Example: “I need to step out of the meeting to take this phone call.” In pop culture Did you ever wonder how women of the 1980s exercised? Watch this ad for Jane Fonda’s Step Aerobic Workout: There are other meanings of step. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: grate</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/17/intermediate-word-of-the-day-grate/"/>
        <id>post-15640</id>
        <updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>grate (verb, noun) /greɪt/ LISTEN Most commonly, grate means ‘to reduce something to small pieces by rubbing it against a sharp surface with small holes.’ But grate also means ‘to make a harsh, annoying sound by rubbing two things together’ and it is used figuratively to mean that something or someone has an irritating effect. As a noun, grate is a frame of metal bars, used in fireplaces or stoves, or a metal framework in windows. Example sentences Henry grated some cheese to go on top of the pizza. The old, rusty gate grated against its hinges, as Julie pushed it open. There&#039;s something about Peter&#039;s voice that I can&#039;t stand; it really grates. We lit the fire last night, so the grate needs cleaning out. The windows were fitted with ornate grates. Words often used with grate grate on someone, grate on someone’s nerves: to irritate someone. Example: “The way he is always tapping his fingers really grates on me,” or “The way he is always tapping his fingers really grates on my nerves.” In pop culture Listen to The Pet Shop Boys with their song “Up Against It” here. Listen out for the lyric “The longer you hate, the more that it grates.” Did you know? You can grate cheese or vegetables, but if you are taking little pieces off of the peel of a fruit, especially a citrus fruit like a lemon, lime, or orange, we use the verb zest instead of grate. The noun zest refers to the little pieces of the peel. Example: “Zest the lemon. Then add the zest to the mixture.” There is a special kitchen tool called a zester, which you can use for zesting, but a small grater also works very well and has more uses in the kitchen. Other forms grater (noun), grated (adjective) Origin Grate, meaning ‘to scrape or rub,’ dates back to the late 14th century. It came into English from the Old French grater (‘to scrape or scratch off,’ ‘to erase’ or ‘to destroy’), and can be traced back to the Frankish kratton, from the Proto-Germanic krattojan. Its origin before then is uncertain, but most linguists agree that it was probably imitative. Grate is related to the Old High German krazzon (to scratch or scrape), the German kratzen (to scratch), the Swedish kratta, Danish kratte (to rake or scrape), the French gratter (to scrape or scratch) and the Italian grattare (to scrape or scratch). The senses ‘to make a harsh sound’ and ‘to annoy or irritate’ both appeared in the mid-16th century. The noun, originally meaning ‘a grill for cooking,’ also dates back to the late 14th century. Linguists disagree on whether it came into English from the Old French grate, which evolved from the Medieval Latin grāta (grating or lattice), or directly from the Medieval Latin. Either way, it can be traced back to the Latin cratis (wickerwork or hurdle) and the Proto-Indo-European root kert– (to weave or twist together). Grate is related to the Italian grata, as well as the Sanskrit krt (to spin), the Greek kartalos (a of basket) and kyrtos (fishing creel), and the English words cartilage, crate and hurdle. See full definition Learn more about grate in our forums Grate in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: stretch</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/17/basic-word-of-the-day-stretch/"/>
        <id>post-15662</id>
        <updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>stretch (verb, noun) /past tense: stretched/ LISTEN It&#039;s important to stretch before exercising. Stretch means ‘to straighten or extend the body.’ The runner stretches before his daily run. When the cat woke up, she stretched her body and meowed. Stretch can mean ‘to extend from one place to another.’ The forest stretches from the mountains to the ocean. The line of customers for the new phone stretched around the block. Stretch also means ‘to extend too much.’ After Frieda wore her jeans three days in a row, they were stretched in the knees. Stretch can also mean ‘an extended amount of time.’ Felix did a ten-year stretch in prison for armed robbery. Ted was in the navy for a stretch of four years. Common uses stretch the truth: say something that exaggerates the facts. Example: “The fisherman stretched the truth when he described the size of the trout that he caught.” In pop culture A stretch limousine is a very long car used for driving people around. The movie Stretch is about a stretch limo driver who needs a lot of money–fast. Watch the trailer: There are other meanings of stretch. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: foil</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/16/intermediate-word-of-the-day-foil/"/>
        <id>post-15639</id>
        <updated>2022-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>foil (verb, noun) /fɔɪl/ LISTEN A person fencing, using a foil Foil is a roll of extremely thin sheet metal used mainly to wrap food. It is also a person or a thing that serves as a contrast and makes another person or thing look better. As a verb, to foil means ‘to frustrate and prevent the success of a plan.’ A foil is also a flexible sword used in the sport fencing. Example sentences Jamie wrapped the leftovers in foil and put them in the fridge. In famous comic duos, there is usually a &quot;straight man&quot; and a comedian. The straight man does not tell jokes and is a foil for the comedian. Their plans for a picnic were foiled by bad weather. The two women took up their foils and began to fence. Words often used with foil The food wrap is more fully known as aluminum foil in the US and aluminium foil in the UK. Especially in the UK, people also sometimes call it tinfoil. In pop culture Watch comedian and singer-songwriter Weird Al Yankovic performing his song “Foil,” in praise of the stuff used for wrapping food, here: Additional information As a verb, foil can also mean ‘to apply foil’ or ‘to cover something in foil.’ Did you know? Fencing has been practiced for centuries, mostly as a way men learned how to duel (ie, fight between two people with weapons) and defend themselves. Some believe that, at the end of the Roman Empire, German soldiers spread the practice of resolving arguments by dueling, so learning how to fight with a sword became essential. In some places, dueling was prohibited in the 15th century, but the tradition of fencing continued. It began to be seen as a sport in the 18th century, and it has been an Olympic sport since the first modern Olympic Games were held, in 1896.   Origin The verb foil, originally meaning ‘to spoil a trace or scent by running over it,’ dates back to around the year 1300, as the Middle English verb foilen (another related verb, defoilen, actually meant the same thing and was more common). It came into English from the Old French foler or fuler (‘to trample on, injure or maim,’ and figuratively, ‘to treat badly, deceive or get the better of someone’), and can be traced back to the Vulgar Latin fullāre (to clean cloth by treading on it) and the Latin fullo (a person who cleans cloth), though its origin before then is uncertain. The sense expanded to the more general ‘to overthrow or defeat’ and ‘to frustrate the efforts of someone’ in the mid-16th century. The noun foil, meaning ‘a very thin sheet of metal,’ dates back to the early 14th century, as the Middle English foile. It came into English from the Old French foil, fueill or fueille (leaf, foliage, sheet or paper or sheet of metal), and can be traced back to the Latin folia, the plural of folium (leaf) and the Proto-Indo-European root bhel– (to thrive or bloom). Foil is related to the French fueille, the Italian foglia, the Portuguese folha and the Spanish hoja (all meaning ‘leaf’ or ‘sheet of paper or metal’), as well as the Greek phyllon (leaf), the Latin flos (flower) and derived Romance language terms like the Spanish flor and the French fleur, the Middle Irish blath and Welsh blawd (blossom or flower), the Gaelic bile (leaflet or blossom), and English words such as blade, bleed, bless, blow, blood, bloom, blossom, exfoliate, floral, flour, flower and portfolio. The sense ‘person or thing that makes another look better by contrast’ appeared in the late 16th century, and is a figurative use of the practice of backing a gem with foil to make it shine brighter. The sense ‘metallic food wrap’ was first used in the late 19th century. The verb foil, meaning ‘to apply foil,’ dates back to the early 17th century and comes from the noun. Foil, meaning ‘a light sword used in fencing,’ dates back to the late 16th century. Linguists actually disagree on whether it comes from the noun sense (a thin sheet of metal) or from the verb (to frustrate or prevent success). See full definition Learn more about foil in our forums Foil in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: ink</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/16/basic-word-of-the-day-ink/"/>
        <id>post-15661</id>
        <updated>2022-05-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>ink (noun, verb) past tense: inked LISTEN &quot;Cool ink!&quot; Ink is a fluid used for writing or drawing. George filled his fountain pen with black ink. The artist prefers drawing with pen and ink rather than pencil. Ink also means ‘to draw or write with ink.’ The lawyer inked the contract. Common uses Before the ink is dry: after signing an agreement, things change very quickly. Example: “The newly married couple realized that they had made a big mistake before the ink was dry.” Did you know? People refer to their tattoos as their ink. Watch this video where Post Malone describes his ink: In pop culture The Ink Spots was a popular singing group in the 1930s and 1940s. In this video, they sing “If I Didn’t Care.” The lyrics are in the comments below the video: There are other meanings of ink. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: slum</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/13/intermediate-word-of-the-day-slum/"/>
        <id>post-15581</id>
        <updated>2022-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>slum (noun, verb, adjective) /slʌm/ LISTEN A slum, often in the plural form slums, is usually an overpopulated part of a city where people live in extremely poor conditions. The word is common, but inhabitants of these areas often do not like their neighborhood to be referred to this way because of its derogatory connotation. Slum is used figuratively to talk about any place where living conditions are unpleasant or dirty. Slum can also be used like an adjective, to describe something related to a slum or someone who lives in one. Example sentences Many poor people live in the slums and can&#039;t afford to move to a different neighborhood. You should see her house; it&#039;s an absolute slum! The mayor vowed that all the slum properties would be demolished and replaced with modern homes. A group of slum kids was playing outside one of the houses. Words often used with slum slum it: to visit places below your social status or to put up with standards of comfort that are less than you are used to; this informal expression is common, especially among younger people, but some people consider it offensive. Example: “I know the accommodation isn’t very good, but we can manage to slum it for a couple of nights, can’t we?” slum conditions: the conditions of living in a slum. Example: “The slum conditions of the house next door lowers the value of all the houses on the block.” slum-dweller: a person who lives in a slum. Example: “Although he was a slum-dweller as a child, he became a successful doctor.” slumlord: an informal way to refer to a landlord who owns slum properties and rents them out to people. Example: “The slumlord charged high rents but did not maintain the building properly.” In pop culture Listen to The Kinks singing their song “Slum Kids” here: Did you know? Brazil is especially known for its slums, which are called favelas in Portuguese (and often referred to with that word in English). In Rio de Janeiro, a few of these neighborhoods have some of the best views in the city, and many foreigners are buying houses in them. Other forms slummer (noun) Origin Slum dates back to the early 19th century, and was a slang word that originally meant ‘room,’ particularly ‘back room.’ The sense we use today appeared in the mid-19th century, as a shortened form of the expression back slum (early 19th century), which originally meant ‘dirty back alley in a city’ as well as ‘city of poor people.’ Its use was spread by crime novels set in the East End of London, which were very popular at the time. The verb, meaning ‘to visit slums for disreputable purposes,’ dates back to the mid-19th century. The sense shifted to mean ‘to visit the slums of a city (for entertainment),’ probably also due to popular crime novels, in the late 19th century. See full definition Learn more about slum in our forums Slum in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: lid</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/13/basic-word-of-the-day-lid/"/>
        <id>post-15551</id>
        <updated>2022-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>lid (noun) LISTEN A lid is a removable cover for a container, such as a pot, jar, or box. When Michelle removed the lid of the box, she saw a beautiful knit blanket inside. Max opened the lid on the pickle jar for his grandmother. A lid can also be an eyelid (the skin covering the eye). Jenny put brown eye shadow on her lids. A lid can also be a restraint or limit on spending. The accounting department put a lid on expenses for the rest of the year. Common uses flip my lid: become crazed or lose control. Example: “If another person spells ‘it’s’ wrong, I’ll flip my lid!” Did you know? You have a jar of premium chocolate sauce and you can’t open the lid. What to do? Watch this video: In pop culture Watch this old comedy routine “Where Is the Lid,” with Hugh Laurie and Stephen Fry. There are other meanings of lid. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: bench</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/12/intermediate-word-of-the-day-bench/"/>
        <id>post-15580</id>
        <updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>bench (noun, verb) /bɛntʃ/ LISTEN A bench is a long seat for three or four people, often found in parks and public spaces. It is also a judge’s seat and it is used figuratively as a symbol of a judge’s power. In sports, it is the seat where the team members who are not playing sit. As a verb, in US English, to bench somebody means ‘to remove somebody from a sports game,’ but it is also used informally to mean ‘to remove someone from any other situation.’ Example sentences The three girls sat on the bench in the park to eat their lunch. The judge entered the courtroom and sat on the bench. That lady used to be a judge; she served on the bench for 30 years. The substitutes were waiting on the bench, hoping they would get a chance to play. The coach had to bench the midfielder after he committed three consecutive fouls. The manager benched half of the sales team when he heard they&#039;d been telling lies about the competition. Words often used with bench bench press: This is an exercise where someone lies on a bench and pushes a weight (called a barbell) up and down with their arms; this can also be a verb for the action of pushing the weight up and down. Colloquially, the verb can be shortened to just bench. Example: “I can bench 215 pounds.” workbench: a sturdy (ie, extremely stable) table where an artisan works. Example: “The potter painted the vase at her workbench.” In pop culture If a member of a sports team is usually on the bench, you can humorously refer to them as a benchwarmer (because they are keeping the bench warm). The Benchwarmers is the title of a 2006 movie, and you can watch the trailer for it here: Additional information Bench also means ‘to exhibit a dog at a dog show,’ because the platform where the animals are placed during the show is also called a bench. Example: “The trainer plans to bench his toy poodle at several dog shows this year.” Informally, in sports, bench can refer not just to the actual bench where the substitute players sit, but also the players themselves. Example: “The team is successful because they have a deep bench.” Did you know? The long seats where politicians sit in the British Houses of Parliament are called benches. Senior politicians or spokespeople for their parties sit on the front bench (they are known as frontbenchers) and less senior members sit farther back, on the back benches (they are known as backbenchers). Frontbench and backbench are also used as adjectives to describe actions undertaken by the people who sit on the front or back benches. Example: “This frontbench policy has met with a lot of backbench opposition.” Origin Bench dates back to before the year 1000, in the form of the Old English noun benc (Middle English benk, bynk or bench), which meant ‘long seat’ (especially one without a back). It can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic bankiz (bench) and the Proto-Indo-European root b(h)ewg(h)– (to bend or curve). Bench is related to the Old Frisian bank, the Old Norse bekkr, the Danish bænk, the Middle Dutch banc, the Old High German banch, the Dutch bank, the German Bank, the Danish bænk, the Swedish bänk, the Icelandic bekkur and the Scots benk or bink (all meaning ‘bench’), as well as the English word bank (in the sense of a natural incline on the shore of a body of water). Bench has been used to refer to the place where judges sit since around the year 1300, and this sense extended to ‘the office of a judge’ and to ‘judges collectively’ in the 14th century. The sports sense was first used in the US in the late 19th century to refer to the physical place where players sat during a game, and extended to ‘the players not in the game’ in the early 20th century. The verb dates back to the mid-19th century, and comes from the noun. It originally meant ‘to display a dog in a dog show,’ though that sense is no longer in use. The current meaning, ‘to take a player out of a game,’ was first used in the US in the early 20th century. See full definition Learn more about bench in our forums Bench in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: lack</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/12/basic-word-of-the-day-lack/"/>
        <id>post-15550</id>
        <updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>lack (noun, verb) past tense: lacked LISTEN This room lacks furniture. Lack is the absence of something needed or desirable. The lack of attention made the dog bark loudly. When Fred has a lack of sleep, he can&#039;t think clearly. Lack means ‘to be in need of’ or ‘to be without.’ Amanda&#039;s boss lacks leadership skills. Rick needs a new car, but he lacks the money to pay for one. What we lack in experience we make up for in enthusiasm. Don&#039;t confuse it with luck: good fortune. Example: “Claire had the good luck to win the lottery.” Related words lackluster: boring, not lively. Example: “The concert performance was lackluster; it seemed like the conductor lacked energy.” In pop culture Listen to Death Cab for Cutie sing “Lack of Color.” Perhaps someone who is lonely feels like the world lacks color. How do you interpret the title of this song? There are other meanings of lack. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
    </feed>
