<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Daily WordReference</title>
    <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/"/>
    <updated>2022-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>WordReference</name>
    </author>
    <id>id</id>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: slum</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/13/intermediate-word-of-the-day-slum/"/>
        <id>post-15581</id>
        <updated>2022-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>slum (noun, verb, adjective) /slʌm/ LISTEN A slum, often in the plural form slums, is a usually an overpopulated part of a city where people live in extremely poor conditions. The word is common, but inhabitants of these areas often do not like their neighborhood to be referred to this way because of its derogatory connotation. Slum is used figuratively to talk about any place where living conditions are unpleasant or dirty. Slum can also be used like an adjective, to describe something related to a slum or someone who lives in one. Example sentences Many poor people live in the slums and can&#039;t afford to move to a different neighborhood. You should see her house; it&#039;s an absolute slum! The mayor vowed that all the slum properties would be demolished and replaced with modern homes. A group of slum kids was playing outside one of the houses. Words often used with slum slum it: to visit places below your social status or to put up with standards of comfort that are less than you are used to; this informal expression is common, especially among younger people, but some people consider it offensive. Example: “I know the accommodation isn’t very good, but we can manage to slum it for a couple of nights, can’t we?” slum conditions: the conditions of living in a slum. Example: “The slum conditions of the house next door lowers the value of all the houses on the block.” slum-dweller: a person who lives in a slum. Example: “Although he was a slum-dweller as a child, he became a successful doctor.” slumlord: an informal way to refer to a landlord who owns slum properties and rents them out to people. Example: “The slumlord charged high rents but did not maintain the building properly.” In pop culture Listen to The Kinks singing their song “Slum Kids” here: Did you know? Brazil is especially known for its slums, which are called favelas in Portuguese (and often referred to with that word in English). In Rio de Janeiro, a few of these neighborhoods have some of the best views in the city, and many foreigners are buying houses in them. Other forms slummer (noun) Origin Slum dates back to the early 19th century, and was a slang word that originally meant ‘room,’ particularly ‘back room.’ The sense we use today appeared in the mid-19th century, as a shortened form of the expression back slum (early 19th century), which originally meant ‘dirty back alley in a city’ as well as ‘city of poor people.’ Its use was spread by crime novels set in the East End of London, which were very popular at the time. The verb, meaning ‘to visit slums for disreputable purposes,’ dates back to the mid-19th century. The sense shifted to mean ‘to visit the slums of a city (for entertainment),’ probably also due to popular crime novels, in the late 19th century. See full definition Learn more about slum in our forums Slum in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: lid</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/13/basic-word-of-the-day-lid/"/>
        <id>post-15551</id>
        <updated>2022-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>lid (noun) LISTEN A lid is a removable cover for a container, such as a pot, jar, or box. When Michelle removed the lid of the box, she saw a beautiful knit blanket inside. Max opened the lid on the pickle jar for his grandmother. A lid can also be an eyelid (the skin covering the eye). Jenny put brown eye shadow on her lids. A lid can also be a restraint or limit on spending. The accounting department put a lid on expenses for the rest of the year. Common uses flip my lid: become crazed or lose control. Example: “If another person spells ‘it’s’ wrong, I’ll flip my lid!” Did you know? You have a jar of premium chocolate sauce and you can’t open the lid. What to do? Watch this video: In pop culture Watch this old comedy routine “Where Is the Lid,” with Hugh Laurie and Stephen Fry. There are other meanings of lid. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: bench</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/12/intermediate-word-of-the-day-bench/"/>
        <id>post-15580</id>
        <updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>bench (noun, verb) /bɛntʃ/ LISTEN A bench is a long seat for three or four people, often found in parks and public spaces. It is also a judge’s seat and it is used figuratively as a symbol of a judge’s power. In sports, it is the seat where the team members who are not playing sit. As a verb, in US English, to bench somebody means ‘to remove somebody from a sports game,’ but it is also used informally to mean ‘to remove someone from any other situation.’ Example sentences The three girls sat on the bench in the park to eat their lunch. The judge entered the courtroom and sat on the bench. That lady used to be a judge; she served on the bench for 30 years. The substitutes were waiting on the bench, hoping they would get a chance to play. The coach had to bench the midfielder after he committed three consecutive fouls. The manager benched half of the sales team when he heard they&#039;d been telling lies about the competition. Words often used with bench bench press: This is an exercise where someone lies on a bench and pushes a weight (called a barbell) up and down with their arms; this can also be a verb for the action of pushing the weight up and down. Colloquially, the verb can be shortened to just bench. Example: “I can bench 215 pounds.” workbench: a sturdy (ie, extremely stable) table where an artisan works. Example: “The potter painted the vase at her workbench.” In pop culture If a member of a sports team is usually on the bench, you can humorously refer to them as a benchwarmer (because they are keeping the bench warm). The Benchwarmers is the title of a 2006 movie, and you can watch the trailer for it here: Additional information Bench also means ‘to exhibit a dog at a dog show,’ because the platform where the animals are placed during the show is also called a bench. Example: “The trainer plans to bench his toy poodle at several dog shows this year.” Informally, in sports, bench can refer not just to the actual bench where the substitute players sit, but also the players themselves. Example: “The team is successful because they have a deep bench.” Did you know? The long seats where politicians sit in the British Houses of Parliament are called benches. Senior politicians or spokespeople for their parties sit on the front bench (they are known as frontbenchers) and less senior members sit farther back, on the back benches (they are known as backbenchers). Frontbench and backbench are also used as adjectives to describe actions undertaken by the people who sit on the front or back benches. Example: “This frontbench policy has met with a lot of backbench opposition.” Origin Bench dates back to before the year 1000, in the form of the Old English noun benc (Middle English benk, bynk or bench), which meant ‘long seat’ (especially one without a back). It can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic bankiz (bench) and the Proto-Indo-European root b(h)ewg(h)– (to bend or curve). Bench is related to the Old Frisian bank, the Old Norse bekkr, the Danish bænk, the Middle Dutch banc, the Old High German banch, the Dutch bank, the German Bank, the Danish bænk, the Swedish bänk, the Icelandic bekkur and the Scots benk or bink (all meaning ‘bench’), as well as the English word bank (in the sense of a natural incline on the shore of a body of water). Bench has been used to refer to the place where judges sit since around the year 1300, and this sense extended to ‘the office of a judge’ and to ‘judges collectively’ in the 14th century. The sports sense was first used in the US in the late 19th century to refer to the physical place where players sat during a game, and extended to ‘the players not in the game’ in the early 20th century. The verb dates back to the mid-19th century, and comes from the noun. It originally meant ‘to display a dog in a dog show,’ though that sense is no longer in use. The current meaning, ‘to take a player out of a game,’ was first used in the US in the early 20th century. See full definition Learn more about bench in our forums Bench in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: lack</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/12/basic-word-of-the-day-lack/"/>
        <id>post-15550</id>
        <updated>2022-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>lack (noun, verb) past tense: lacked LISTEN This room lacks furniture. Lack is the absence of something needed or desirable. The lack of attention made the dog bark loudly. When Fred has a lack of sleep, he can&#039;t think clearly. Lack means ‘to be in need of’ or ‘to be without.’ Amanda&#039;s boss lacks leadership skills. Rick needs a new car, but he lacks the money to pay for one. What we lack in experience we make up for in enthusiasm. Don&#039;t confuse it with luck: good fortune. Example: “Claire had the good luck to win the lottery.” Related words lackluster: boring, not lively. Example: “The concert performance was lackluster; it seemed like the conductor lacked energy.” In pop culture Listen to Death Cab for Cutie sing “Lack of Color.” Perhaps someone who is lonely feels like the world lacks color. How do you interpret the title of this song? There are other meanings of lack. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: curse</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/11/intermediate-word-of-the-day-curse/"/>
        <id>post-15579</id>
        <updated>2022-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>curse (noun, verb) /kɜrs/ LISTEN A woman cursing at other drivers A curse is something that is said to cause someone misfortune or, figuratively, something that causes pain and trouble. It also means ‘swearword.’ As a verb, to curse means both ‘to wish misfortune upon someone or something’ or ‘to say one or more swearwords.’ In addition, it means ‘to complain about something, possibly using swearwords.’ Example sentences The witch put a curse on the whole village and they had nothing but bad luck after that. This year, my grandma got sick, my mom lost her job, our house flooded, and then our dog died; it&#039;s like there&#039;s a curse on us! Raphaël hit his thumb with the hammer and let out a stream of curses. The witch cursed the young prince, and he turned into a frog. The young man was clearly very angry and was cursing at everybody. When Alison lost her job, she cursed the day she ever met her boss. Words often used with curse be cursed with: suffer from. Example: “She was cursed with two left feet and couldn’t dance at all!” be cursed to: have to do something because of a curse. Example: “The princess was cursed to sleep for one hundred years.” In pop culture Watch a clip from the claymation (clay animation) movie Wallace and Gromit: The Curse of the Were-Rabbit here: Additional information If you say “John cursed” or “John cursed at someone,” it means that John is using swearwords; curse in this sense is an exact synonym of the verb swear. However, in the expression “John cursed somebody (or something),” then John is specifically wishing that person or thing ill or complaining about them; if John has magical powers, it can also mean that John put a curse on them. Did you know? Menstruation is colloquially known as “the curse.” This is sometimes assumed to be because God cursed Eve with menstruation for eating the forbidden fruit, but actually God cursed Eve with pain in childbirth. However, religions have often created taboos around menstruation, so there may be a connection. There are many other euphemisms to refer to menstruation, such as Aunt Flo (normally in the phrases “Aunt Flo is in town” or “Aunt Flo is visiting”) or somebody might say she “has the painters and decorators in.” These euphemisms are sometimes considered old fashioned, and many women just say “I have my period” (period is another word for the menstrual cycle). Other forms curser (noun) Origin Curse dates back to before the year 1050, in the form of the Old and Middle English noun curs. Its origin is uncertain. There are no related Germanic, Romance or Celtic words. In late Old English, curs meant ‘a prayer that evil or harm should come to someone,’ so some linguists think curse may have come from the Latin cursus (course), which was the name given to the ‘set of daily liturgical prayers,’ and used in the ‘sentence of the great curse,’ which was the formula read in churches to excommunicate offenders four times a year. Other linguists have proposed a relation to the Old French curuz (anger), but there is scant evidence for it, and some have also suggested a link to the word cross, but this is considered highly unlikely. The senses ‘evil invoked upon someone’ and ‘something that causes severe trouble’ both appeared in the 14th century. Curses (always in plural), has been used as a histrionic exclamation wince the mid-17th century, and the sense of curse as a swearword evolved from this use. The curse, as the sentence imposed on Adam and Eve in the Bible, was first recorded in the 19th century, and the curse as a euphemism for menstruation has been used since the 1930s. The verb also dates back to before the year 1050, in the form of the Old English cursian and later the Middle English cursen. It came from the same (unknown) source as the noun. See full definition Learn more about curse in our forums Curse in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: sail</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/11/basic-word-of-the-day-sail/"/>
        <id>post-15549</id>
        <updated>2022-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>sail (noun, verb) past tense: sailed LISTEN A sail is a piece of cloth on a boat or ship to catch the wind. The ship had three sails. The sail moved back and forth in the gentle wind. Sail means ‘to travel in a ship.’ The cruise ship sailed through the Panama Canal. Columbus sailed from Spain with three ships. Sail can also mean ‘to move like a sailing ship.’ Taylor sailed into the room and took over the meeting. Don&#039;t confuse it with sale: an offering of goods at reduced prices. Example: “During the sale, prices are reduced by 50 percent.” Common uses set sail for: to start a voyage. Example: “The sailors set sail for the island at dawn.” Related words sailor: a person in the navy whose rank is below officer. Example: “The sailor communicated with the other ships in the area.” In pop culture Do you know the series Sailor Moon? It’s based on a Japanese manga series and it’s about the adventures of a schoolgirl who tries to avoid the destruction of the Solar System. Here’s the opening song in English: There are other meanings of sail. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: nag</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/10/intermediate-word-of-the-day-nag/"/>
        <id>post-15578</id>
        <updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>nag (verb, noun) /næg/ LISTEN Teenagers often think their parents are nagging them. Nag is a word used informally among native speakers. It means ‘to annoy by constant demands or criticism,’ or ‘to be the cause of pain, irritation, or unease.’ Even more informally, a nag is a person who nags and irritates other people all the time. Example sentences Every summer my husband nags me about putting on sunblock; he&#039;s right of course, because I burn easily and I always forget! Henry went to see the doctor about a pain that had been nagging him for some time. The painter was always nagged by doubts about how good her work was. My boss is such a nag and never just leaves us alone to get on with the job. Words often used with nag You can also use nag without a direct object, in which case it takes the preposition “at.” Example: “The idea that she had left the oven on kept nagging at Frances.” Nag is also used without an object and with the adverb “on” to mean that someone keeps nagging. Example: “Teenagers often complain that their parents are always nagging on about how much TV they watch.” In pop culture Listen to Joan Jett and the Blackhearts singing “Nag” here: Additional information A nag is also a horse, usually an old horse that someone considers worthless. Did you know? When talking about a person nagging or being a nag, the word used to mainly be associated with women. However, in these less sexist times, most people recognize that both men and women can nag a lot! Other forms nagger (noun) Origin Nag, meaning ‘to annoy by scolding,’ is a relatively new term, and dates back to the early 19th century. Its origin is uncertain, but it is thought to have evolved from a dialectal term, nag, that meant ‘to gnaw,’ and probably came from a Scandinavian source. As such, it can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic gnagan (to gnaw). Nag is related to the Old Norse gnaga (‘to complain,’ but literally ‘to bite or gnaw’) and the dialectal Swedish and Norwegian nagga (to gnaw), as well as the Old Saxon gnagan, the Old Norse and Swedish gnaga, the Middle Dutch and Dutch knagen, the Old High German gnagan and the German nagen (all meaning ‘to gnaw’), and of course the English word gnaw. The noun meaning ‘a person who nags’ dates back to the mid-19th century, and comes from the verb. Nag, meaning ‘a riding pony’ and ‘an old horse,’ dates back to around the year 1400, in the form of the Middle English noun nagge. Its origin is uncertain, but it is thought to be related to the word neigh, of imitative origin. See full definition Learn more about nag in our forums Nag in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: ring</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/10/basic-word-of-the-day-ring/"/>
        <id>post-15548</id>
        <updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>ring (noun, verb) past tense: rang LISTEN A ring is a circular band, usually of gold or another metal, worn on the finger. Marie&#039;s engagement ring had an emerald and two small diamonds. George wore the class ring that he got when he graduated from the university. A ring can be something shaped like a ring. The children held hands and danced in a ring. The cigar smoker blew smoke rings. Ring also means ‘to make a loud echoing sound as that of a bell.’ Someone is ringing the doorbell. Would you please answer it? The church bells ring before Sunday mass. Common uses give someone a ring: to call someone on the telephone. Example: “I don’t know if we can come to your party, but I’ll give you a ring as soon as I know.” Did you know? A boxing ring is the space where a boxing (fighting with padded gloves) match takes place. Modern boxing rings are square, but we still call them rings because in the past, people fought inside a circle drawn on the ground. In pop culture Listen to Johnny Cash sing “Ring of Fire.” This song compares love to a ring of fire. Do you think that is a good comparison? There are other meanings of ring. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: blend</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/09/intermediate-word-of-the-day-blend/"/>
        <id>post-15583</id>
        <updated>2022-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>blend (verb, noun) /blɛnd/ LISTEN A woman using a blender To blend means ‘to mix two or more things smoothly‘ or ‘to combine in a really nice way.’ It also means ‘to have no separation that can be easily seen.’ As a noun, you might have heard the word blend in wines or teas; this is because blend means ‘a mixture produced by blending.’ Example sentences Leave the soup to simmer for fifteen minutes and then blend it until smooth. The artist blended the colors skillfully. The choir&#039;s voices blended perfectly. Some animals have coloring that allows them to blend into the background. Saint-Émilion is a wine made from a blend of grape varieties. In pop culture A blended family is one where the parents have children from previous relationships. The movie Blended is about the beginnings of such a family, and you can watch the trailer for it here: Additional information In linguistics, a blend is a word made up of a combination of two words, like brunch, which is made up of breakfast and lunch. Words like this are also called portmanteau words. Did you know? A blender is a common kitchen appliance. It is the tall, motorized machine that you can use to make juice, smoothies, milkshakes, etc. There is also a similar appliance called a stick blender, or immersion blender, which has a similar effect but is much smaller and can be held in the hand and immersed, or put, into the thing you are blending. Other forms blender (noun) Origin Blend, meaning ‘to mix something until the parts become indistinguishable’ or ‘to stir a liquid,’ dates back to around the year 1300, in the form of the Middle English verb blenden. Its origin is uncertain. Some linguists think that it evolved from the Old English blendan or blondan (to mix), while others think it came into English from the (related) Old Norse blanda (to mix). It’s possible that it evolved as a combination of both. Either way, blend can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic blandan (‘to mix,’ literally ‘to make cloudy’) and the Proto-Indo-European root bhel– (to shine, flash or burn), and is related to the Old Saxon and Old High German blantan (to mix), the Middle Dutch blanden (to mix), the Gothic blandan (to mix), the Old Church Slavonic blesti (to go astray), the German Blendling (bastard or mongrel) and the Danish blande (to mix), as well as the Sanskrit bhrajate (shines), the Greek phlegein (to burn), the Latin flamma (flame), fulmen (lightning) and fulgere (to shine or flash), the Lithuanian balnas (pale) and blandus (troubled, stupid or thick), and English words such as black, blanch, blanket, blaze, bleach, bleak, blind, blond, blue, blushflagrant, flame and flamingo. The figurative sense, ‘to mingle closely,’ first appeared in the early 14th century. The noun, meaning ‘a mixture formed by blending,’ comes from the verb, and dates back to the mid-19th century. See full definition Learn more about blend in our forums Blend in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: fate</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/09/basic-word-of-the-day-fate/"/>
        <id>post-15547</id>
        <updated>2022-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>fate (noun) LISTEN I see your fate in the crystal ball. Someone’s fate is something that unavoidably happens to that person. Trevor&#039;s fate was determined by the choices he made as a teenager. Fate also means ‘destiny.’ Sally knew that it was her fate to become president of the country. It was Leslie&#039;s fate to marry Mike. Fate can also mean ‘death’ or ‘destruction.’ Many soldiers met their fate at the Battle of Gettysburg. Don&#039;t confuse it with faith: belief in the teachings of a religion. Example: “The Jedi had faith in the Force.” Common uses fate worse than death: a tragedy that would make life not worth living. Example: “When the soldiers arrived, the villagers suffered a fate worse than death.” In pop culture A twist of fate is an everyday event that happens by chance and is strange or has major importance. A Simple Twist of Fate is also a movie about a small child who wanders into a man’s home and it changes his life. Watch the trailer for this movie. There are other meanings of fate. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
    </feed>
