<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    <title>Daily WordReference</title>
    <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/"/>
    <updated>2022-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>WordReference</name>
    </author>
    <id>id</id>

        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: rocket</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/06/intermediate-word-of-the-day-rocket/"/>
        <id>post-15570</id>
        <updated>2022-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>rocket (noun, verb) /ˈrɑkɪt/ LISTEN A rocket is any tube-like device that contains fuel, which burns and makes it fly through the air; it can be used for fireworks, signaling, etc. A rocket is also a space capsule put into orbit. As a verb, it means ‘to transport with a rocket,’ ‘to move very rapidly,’ and, informally, ‘to increase suddenly.’ Rocket has another completely different meaning; as a noun, it is a Mediterranean plant used in green leaf salads, although it is more commonly known as arugula in US English. Example sentences The fireworks display organizers saved a big rocket for the finale. The policeman sent up a rocket as a warning. Crowds of people gathered to see the rocket launch into space. The spaceship was rocketed into orbit. The car rocketed along the highway. Prices have rocketed since last year. Harry added some rocket leaves to his sandwich. Words often used with rocket it’s not rocket science: an expression meaning that something is not really very complicated. Example: “Haven’t you finished doing your homework yet? Come on; it’s not rocket science!” A similar expression with the same meaning is “It’s not brain surgery.” give someone a rocket (UK): reprimand someone severely, get very mad at someone. Example: “The boss gave Joe a rocket when he arrived 30 minutes late for an important meeting.” In pop culture Someone who works on rockets, like a scientist or engineer, is called a rocketeer. The Rocketeer is the title of a 1991 movie and you can see the trailer for it here: Did you know? In English we also have the related word skyrocket. This word can refer to a kind of rocket, but (perhaps more commonly) it is an informal verb meaning ‘to increase a lot’ or ‘to increase astronomically.’ Example: “The cost of US colleges has skyrocketed since my parents were kids.” Skyrocket is the opposite of plummet, one of our first Words of the Day. Other forms rocketlike (adjective) Origin Rocket, meaning ‘a self-propelling device,’ dates back to the early 17th century. It came into English from the Italian rochetto (a bobbin), the diminutive of rocca (a distaff, which is a device used for spinning thread). It is thought to have come into Italian from a Germanic source, and can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic rukkon– and the Proto-Indo-European root rug– (fabric or spun yarn). Rocket is, therefore, related to the Old High German rocko, the Old Norse rokkr, the German Rocken, the Swedish rock and the Icelandic rokkur (all meaning ‘a distaff’). The sense ‘a fuel-propelled device,’ first used for fireworks, dates back to the early 20th century. The verb, which originally meant ‘to attack with rockets,’ dates back to the late 18th century, and comes from the noun. The sense ‘to spring like a rocket’ was first used in the mid-19th century. Rocket, the noun meaning ‘a leafy green plant used in salads,’ is a bit older; it dates back to around the year 1500. It came into English from the Middle French noun roquette, which was in turn borrowed from the Italian rochetta, diminutive for ruca (a type of cabbage). It can be traced back to the Latin eruca (colewort), which is related to ericus (‘hedgehog’ or ‘beam with spikes’) and the Proto-Indo-European root ghers– (to bristle). Rocket, in this sense, is related to the Sanskrit harsate (bristles), the Avestan zarshayamna– (ruffling your feathers) and the Welsh garw (rough), as well as the English arugula and many other modern terms for the plant, and the English word horror. See full definition Learn more about rocket in our forums Rocket in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: former</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/06/basic-word-of-the-day-former/"/>
        <id>post-15539</id>
        <updated>2022-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>former (adjective, noun) LISTEN His former girlfriend moved out. Former means ‘having been in the past.’ Eric&#039;s former boss is now working for another company. Thomas&#039;s former school is hosting his class reunion. Former also means ‘being the first of two mentioned.’ (The second is the latter). The former choice was better than the latter. Common uses a shell of his/her former self: someone who has changed for the worse, usually because of a traumatic experience. Example: “After the war, Scarlett was a shell of her former self.” Did you know? Ex– is a more casual way to say former. For example: “Dan’s ex-wife is the mother of his oldest daughter.” And when referring to a former spouse or partner, someone may just say ex. For example: “Oh no! There’s my ex. We need to leave immediately.” In pop culture The five former presidents of the US spoke at a charity concert to help victims of Hurricane Harvey in Texas. You can hear Bill Clinton and Barack Obama speak in this video. There are other meanings of former. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: knack</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/05/intermediate-word-of-the-day-knack/"/>
        <id>post-15569</id>
        <updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>knack (noun) /næk/ LISTEN Sylvia has a knack for math. Knack is a word used informally to mean ‘a skill or ability’ and it can also mean ‘a clever way of doing something.’ Knack also means ‘a particular talent for doing something’ or ‘a tendency to do something.’ Example sentences Sylvia has a real knack with children; they adore her. The washing machine does work, but you have to press the button a certain way; there&#039;s a knack to it. Alicia has a knack for computer programming and works for a tech company in San Francisco. Melanie has a knack of picking the wrong boyfriends; they always end up breaking her heart. In pop culture Listen to the Knack’s “My Sharona” here: Don&#039;t confuse it with The term knackered sounds similar but means something completely different. It is very common in the UK, especially in informal conversation, and means ‘extremely tired.’ For example, “I was knackered last night and slept for 12 hours.” It is not very common in the US, where we would just say “really tired” or something similar. Did you know? Knack can be used with either “for” or “of” when talking about a talent or tendency. Some dictionaries say that “knack of” should be used with a behavior or tendency (ie, “a knack of picking the wrong boyfriends”) and “knack for” should be used for a skill (ie, “a knack for computer programming”), but many native speakers don’t know about this rule. Origin Knack, which originally meant ‘a deception, trick or device,’ dates back to the mid-14th century. Its origin is uncertain, but some linguists think it may have come from another, slightly older (early 14th century) Middle English word, knak or knakke, which meant ‘a sharp-sounding blow or sound,’ which probably came into English from a Germanic language, and was originally imitative. Knack is possibly related to the German knacken (to crack), and the English words knap (a sharp-sounding blow) and crack. The sense ‘a special ability for something’ was first used in the late 16th century, though some linguists actually think knack in this sense could have been a separate word, also of unknown origin. See full definition Learn more about knack in our forums Knack in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: jar</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/05/basic-word-of-the-day-jar/"/>
        <id>post-15538</id>
        <updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>jar (noun, verb) past tense: jarred LISTEN A jar of pickles A jar is a glass container that you put things in. Martin opened the jar of strawberry jam. Emma took a chocolate chip cookie from the cookie jar. Jar also means ‘to suddenly vibrate or shake.’ The earthquake jarred the house. The fire alarm jarred me from my sleep. Did you know? Some homes have a swear jar to discourage family members or roommates from using vulgar language. Every time someone swears (says a bad word), they have to put money in the jar. Related words ajar: slightly opened, when referring to a door. Example: “The door was ajar, so she heard their conversation.” In pop culture Watch this clip from the TV show Glee, which takes place at a high school prom (dance). The song is “Jar of Hearts.” You can sing along with the chorus: “Who do you think you are?/Running around leaving scars/Collecting your jar of hearts/Tearing love apart/ You’re going to catch a cold/From the ice inside your soul/Don’t come back for me.” There are other meanings of jar. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: nail</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/04/intermediate-word-of-the-day-nail/"/>
        <id>post-15568</id>
        <updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>nail (noun, verb) /neɪl/ LISTEN As a noun, a nail is the hard cover on the tip of each of our fingers and toes, as well as a thin piece of metal with a pointed end used to connect things to a wall or to each other. As a verb, nail means not only ‘to fasten or connect something with a nail,’ but also, as slang, ‘to arrest or catch a criminal’ or ‘to achieve something with great success.’ Example sentences I need to cut my nails; they&#039;re getting too long! Helen hammered a nail into the wall so she could hang the picture. Eugene nailed two pieces of wood together. After a car chase, the police finally nailed the bank robbers. I&#039;m sure Patricia will have nailed the exam; she&#039;s worked so hard. Words often used with nail nailed it!: an interjection used to say you have successfully achieved something. Example: “How did your job interview go?” “Nailed it! I start on Monday.” fight tooth and nail: an expression used figuratively to mean you will do everything in your power to achieve or combat something: Example: “The MP fought tooth and nail to get the new law accepted.” “The residents fought tooth and nail against the plans for the new road.” on the nail: immediately. Example: “The seller wanted to be paid cash on the nail.” hit the nail on the head: get something exactly right or understand something correctly. Example: “When you said my problem might be an allergy, you hit the nail on the head; that’s exactly what it turned out to be.” the final nail (in the coffin): the last in a series of misfortunes leading to someone or something’s downfall. Example: “When his van broke down, that was the final nail in the coffin for Alan’s delivery business.” fingernail: a nail on your finger toenail: a nail on your toe In pop culture Watch the trailer for Netflix’s cooking show Nailed It! here: Did you know? As a slang term, nail someone can mean ‘to have sexual intercourse with that person.’ It is normally said of a man having sexual intercourse with a woman. You may hear this a lot in movies and on TV, but it is generally considered demeaning and offensive to talk about someone like this. Other forms nailless (adjective) Origin Nail dates back to before the year 900, in the form of what some linguists believe were two separate Old English nouns: nægl (finger or toenail) and negel (sharp metal pin), which had merged by Middle English, and perhaps even sooner, to nail(i) or nayl(l), which took on both meanings. Other linguists think that they are simply alternate spellings of the same noun, and the original meaning was ‘finger or toenail,’ as well as ‘claw,’ with ‘metal pin’ appearing soon after, a figurative take on claw. Either way, nail can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic naglaz and the Proto-Indo-European root (o)nog(h)– (nail), and is related to the Old Saxon and Old High German nagel, the Old Frisian neil, the Middle Dutch naghel, the Dutch nagel, the German Nagel, the Danish negl and the Swedish nagel (all of which have both meanings of nail), as well as the Greek onyx (claw or fingernail), the Latin unguis (nail or claw), the Spanish uña, Portuguese unha and French ongle (together with other Romance language words for nail or claw), the Old Church Slavonic noga (foot) and noguti (nail or claw), the Lithuanian naga (hoof) and nagutis (fingernail), the Old Irish ingen (nail or claw) and the Old Welsh eguin (nail or claw). The expression ‘to hit the nail on the head’ first appeared in the early 16th century. The verb also dates back to before the year 900, as the Old English næglian, meaning ‘to fasten with nails’ (Middle English naylen or nailen), which can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic ganaglijan, from the same PIE root as the noun. Nail is related to the Old Saxon neglian, the Old Norse negla, the Old High German negilen, the German nageln and the Gothic ganagljan, all meaning ‘to nail.’ The sense ‘to catch’ was first recorded in the mid-18th century, while ‘to succeed’ is from the late 19th century. See full definition Learn more about nail in our forums Nail in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: loose</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/04/basic-word-of-the-day-loose/"/>
        <id>post-15537</id>
        <updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>loose (adjective) LISTEN These jeans are too loose. Loose means ‘not fitting closely or tightly.’ A loose sweater looks good with tight jeans. After she lost weight, Pam&#039;s clothes were loose. Loose also means ‘free or released from being attached.’ Lila had a loose tooth. Don&#039;t confuse it with lose: a verb that means ‘to fail to keep.’ Example: “If you lose your keys you won’t get into the house.” Common uses hang loose: to stay calm (informal). Example: “Hang loose, man. Everything will be okay.” In pop culture Have you seen the movie “Footloose” starring Kevin Bacon? The word ‘footloose’ is an adjective that means “free, carefree,’ and the movie title is a wordplay because the main character is a dancer. There are other meanings of loose. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: lush</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/03/intermediate-word-of-the-day-lush/"/>
        <id>post-15567</id>
        <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>lush (adjective, noun) /lʌʃ/ LISTEN Lush is an adjective that, when used to talk about plants or vegetation, means ‘growing in abundance.’ It also means ‘luxurious’ or ‘rich,’ and in UK English slang it is often used as an interjection meaning ‘excellent,’ ‘cool,’ or ‘very impressive.’ In reference to people, it can mean ‘desirable’ or ‘very attractive.’ As a noun and in informal conversation, a lush is someone who drinks alcohol a lot on a regular basis. Example sentences The forests of Brazil are full of lush vegetation. Geraldine lived in a lush apartment, full of every luxury item you could think of. I like your new car; it&#039;s lush! Neil hated visiting his neighbor, as the man was a lush and his house was littered with empty bottles. In pop culture Listen to K D Lang singing “World of Love” here. Listen out for the lyric “Lavish and lush.” Did you know? The UK slang meaning of lush as ‘cool’ or ‘desirable’ first became very popular in the 1960s, especially among schoolchildren, but it fell out of fashion before being revived in the 1980s. It then fell out of fashion again, before seeing a resurgence around the turn of the 21st century, especially in southern England. Other forms lushly (adverb), lushness (noun) Origin Lush dates back to the mid-15th century, in the form of the Middle English adjective lusch, which meant ‘slack, lax or flaccid,’ as well as ‘soft or tender’ (these senses are now obsolete). Linguists disagree on the origin. Some believe that it came from the Old English lysc or lesc, meaning ‘slack or limp,’ and can be traced back to the Proto-Germanic laskwaz (weak, false or feeble) and the Proto-Indo-European root ley– (to let or to leave behind). If this is the case, lush is related to the Middle Low German lasch (slack), the Middle High German erleswen (to become weak), the Old Norse lǫskr (weak or feeble), the Gothic lasiws (weak or feeble), the Middle Low German las or lasich (slack, languid or idle), the Low German lusch (loose), and the English word lazy. Other linguists think it came into English from the Old French lasche (soft, loose or slack,’ as well as ‘negligent or cowardly’) from the verb laschier (to loosen), and can be traced back to the Late Latin laxicare (to become shaky) and the Latin laxare (to loosen) and luxus (loose), ultimately from the Proto-Indo-European root sleg– (to be slack or languid). In this theory, lush is related to the Greek legein (to leave off or stop) and lagnein (to lust), the Latin languere (to be faint, weary), the Old Church Slavonic slabu (lax or weak), and the Lithuanian silpnas (weak), as well as English words such as languid, languish, lax, lease, relax, release, relish, slack and sleep. The modern sense of the word, ‘luxuriant’ (referring to plants), dates back to around the year 1600, and was first used by William Shakespeare. The noun dates back to the late 18th century. It originally meant ‘liquor,’ and though its origin is uncertain, many linguists think it evolved from a humorous use of the adjective (others think it may be unrelated, and came from a word in Romany). The sense shifted to ‘drunkard’ in the late 19th century. Though it’s no longer used, lush was also a verb in the early to mid-19th century, and meant ‘to drink a lot.’ See full definition Learn more about lush in our forums Lush in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: reach</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/03/basic-word-of-the-day-reach/"/>
        <id>post-15536</id>
        <updated>2022-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>reach (verb) past tense: reached LISTEN Can you reach the leaves? Reach means ‘to stretch to touch something.’ Minnie cannot reach the items on the top shelf. Reach also means ‘to arrive at.’ When you reach Chicago, try the deep dish pizza. The ship reached the port at noon. Reach also means ‘to establish communication with.’ After several attempts, Allison finally reached her uncle. Don&#039;t confuse it with Rich and reach sound similar, but the vowel is different. Rich means ‘having lots of money.’ Example: “The rich man has expensive clothes.” Common uses Out of reach literally means ‘beyond the distance that someone can touch,’ for example: “The knives were out of reach of the little boy.’ But figuratively it means ‘unattainable,’ for example: “The student realized that his goal to read every book in the library was out of reach.” Did you know? If you like American westerns you’ve heard the sheriff say to the bad guys, “Reach for the stars!” That means ‘put your hands up.’ In pop culture Listen to Gloria Estefan sing “Reach.” Does this song make you feel hopeful? There are other meanings of reach. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Intermediate+ Word of the Day: labor (US), labour (UK)</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/02/intermediate-word-of-the-day-labor-us-labour-uk/"/>
        <id>post-15566</id>
        <updated>2022-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>labor (US), labour (UK) (noun, verb, adjective) /ˈleɪbɚ/ LISTEN Labor is a noun that means ‘an activity to produce something’ and it is also the workers paid for doing such activity, considered collectively as a group. It is also physical or mental work, especially when the activity is hard and tiring. Labor is also the last stage in pregnancy, when the baby is born. As a verb, to labor means ‘to work’ and it is mostly used for manual tasks that involve great effort. Figuratively, it means ‘to move really slowly and with effort,’ and it also means ‘to work to achieve a certain goal.’ As an adjective, it refers to everything related to work and workers. Example sentences It takes a lot of labor to build a house! Many farmers complain that it is hard to find extra labor during harvest time. Getting to the top of the steep hill was a real labor. Julie went into labor early, and her baby was born after just eight months of pregnancy. The writer had been laboring over her masterpiece for years. The old man labored over the rough ground. The negotiators labored to reach an agreement. This government has introduced a number of new labor laws. Words often used with labor labor the point: to go over something, especially an argument, too much or in too much detail. Example: “We understand your argument; you can stop laboring the point now!” labor of love: something you make a great effort over because it is very important to you. Example: “The sculptor took months to perfect the statue; it was a real labor of love.” labor under a misapprehension: to be mistaken about something, usually leading you to misunderstand what is being said or is happening. Example: “The tourist couldn’t understand why the staff wouldn’t let him have a room, but in the end he realized he had been laboring under a misapprehension; the hôtel de ville was the town hall and not a hotel!” Did you know? International Workers’ Day, sometimes called Labor Day, is held every year on May 1 (May Day) as a celebration for workers and the working classes. May Day is a public holiday in a lot of countries around the world, and the date was also chosen because it is close to the date of the Haymarket Riot, an initially peaceful workers’ rally that descended into violence, held in Chicago on May 4, 1886. However, some countries celebrate Labor Day on a date that is significant to them; in the United States, for example, Labor Day is the first Monday in September. In pop culture If you’d like to know more about how Labor Day came to be in September in the US, you can find out in this clip from The History Channel’s TV show History of the Holidays: Additional information The Labour Party in the UK is the party that was originally founded to represent working-class people. Other forms laboringly (adverb), laborless (adjective), laborer (noun) Origin Labor, meaning ‘a task or project,’ dates back to around the year 1300, in the form of the Middle English noun labour. It came into English from the Middle French labour and the Old French labor (‘toil, work, task or exertion’ or ‘tribulation or suffering’). It can be traced back to the Latin labōr (‘toil or exertion,’ ‘hardship, pain or fatigue,’ or ‘a work or product of labor’), but its origin before then is uncertain. In English, the senses ‘exertion’ and ‘trouble, difficulty or hardship’ both appeared in the late 14th century. Labor has been used to describe ‘the physical exertions of childbirth’ since the late 16th century; it is short for labor of birth, and similar use exists in other languages. It has been used to describe workers as a collective since the mid-19th century. The verb, meaning ‘to perform work,’ ‘to work hard,’ ‘to keep busy’ or ‘to strive or endeavor to do something,’ dates back to the late 14th century, as the Middle English verb labouren. It came into English from the Old French laborer (‘to work, toil or struggle,’ ‘to be busy’ or ‘to plow land’) which can be traced back to the Latin laborāre (‘to work, take pains or exert yourself,’ ‘to produce by toil,’ ‘to suffer or be afflicted’ or ‘to be in distress’), from the noun labōr. The sense ‘to endure pain or trouble’ was first used in the 15th century, especially in connection with childbirth, and ‘to be burdened’ was first recorded in the late 15th century. See full definition Learn more about labor in our forums Labor in other languages Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Suggest your own word! Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
        <entry>
        <title>Basic+ Word of the Day: work</title>
        <link href="https://daily.wordreference.com/2022/05/02/basic-word-of-the-day-work/"/>
        <id>post-14168</id>
        <updated>2022-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <summary>work (noun, verb) past tense: worked LISTEN People at work Work is something that you have to do. It can be something that someone pays you to do. He’s looking for work. Or it can be something difficult that needs a lot of effort. That’s a lot of work for one person! If you work for someone or for a company, it means that they pay you to do something. She works for a bank. Work can also mean the ‘place that you work.’ I’m at work at the moment. If something works, it means that it isn’t broken. My phone&#039;s old, but it still works. Did you know? Today is International Workers’ Day (sometimes called Labor Day). It is held every year on May 1 (May Day) as a celebration for workers and the working classes. May Day is a public holiday in a lot of countries all over the world. However, some countries celebrate Labor Day on a date that is significant to them; in the United States, for example, Labor Day is the first Monday in September. In pop culture Do you know the song “9 to 5” by Dolly Parton? In the song, she says that lots of people have to work very hard, and their bosses don’t say thank you for it. The song is called “9 to 5” because lots of people have to work from 9:00 in the morning to 5:00 in the evening. Listen for these words: “Working 9 to 5. What a way to make a living.” If you make a living, it means that you work and earn money, so you can buy the things that you need. Related words Housework is all the things that you have to do at home—for example, cleaning and tidying. “My husband does all the housework.” There are other meanings of work. See the full definition! See the translation in your language Spanish French Italian Portuguese German Dutch Swedish Russian Polish Romanian Czech Greek Turkish Chinese Japanese Korean Arabic Please help us make Word of the Day better by answering a few questions. Word of the Day is released Monday through Friday.</summary>
    </entry>
    
</feed>
